free AI YouTube summarizer. Have you ever clicked on a YouTube video thinking it
will be helpful only to realize it's an hour and a half long anywhere like no
thanks. So in this video I'm gonna show you guys how can you easily summarize
YouTube videos. To get it just head over to the Chrome Web Store open a new tab
and type in Chrome extension store click on this website option Chrome Web Store
now here you're gonna find the search box over here type in the extension name
YouTube summarizer by syllabi. It's a free Chrome extension that does the
watching for you and spits out a full transcript summary key points and takeaways
all in seconds. Once you add this extension to your Chrome browser now you can
navigate to the YouTube refresher YouTube page. Now hit towards the YouTube
video that you want to summarize launch it and pay it for a few seconds. Now at the
right hand side of the video you're gonna find this option transcript and
summary. Click on that you'll find the script for the video. Now you have to
click on this robot kind of icon without you'll be directed to a new page. You
can shine up or login or you can just scroll down you'll find the summary as
well as video transcript. I can copy this and hit over to the chat GPT and
give a prompt to provide a new script. This works on any video long lectures,
deep type tutorials, podcasts and documentaries. This tool is not just a
summarizer it's a content goldmine for creative students, marketers and
busy flocks who like working part. So that's a wrap for this video. If the
sky helps you out don't forget to like, share and subscribe. Thanks for
watching.